<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-06T22:19:11+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cookie Blog</title><subtitle>A blog discussing AI and art.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome To Our Cookie Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/intro/2023/03/01/welcome-to-cookie-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome To Our Cookie Blog" /><published>2023-03-01T21:47:55+03:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T21:47:55+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/intro/2023/03/01/welcome-to-cookie-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/intro/2023/03/01/welcome-to-cookie-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sir Potata:&lt;/strong&gt; Hello and welcome to The Cookie Blog. This is where we, two (nerdy) high-school students, voice our opinions about AI art, have fun with it and explain to you readers about what is all the deal going around it. We hope to learn many things, discover ways to use this technology and share our experiences and the knowledge we have acquired on the way.
Now, you might be asking why we picked such a specific topic to write about while there are tons of other topics out there that we can also blog about. First of all, we think that this topic is very important to understand where the world and technology is directing towards. We are still in the beginning of our lives, maybe you are too. I personally have this urge that makes me think about what our future will be like. For the reasons that we will explain in this post, AI is here to stay and will most likely to change our life forever. Also we are pretty much interested in AI art. I (Sir Potata) am mostly interested in the art side of things as my favorite hobby is drawing. I can’t sit still without scribbling more than 20 minutes so you could say that art is important to me. So is what is happening in the art community. I will discuss this in detail with the later posts but to sum it up, there is a big uprising among the artists.  Kuyta is more on the AI side of things, he is our tech guy here (and the bigger nerd lol). Everything about computers, he probably knows, if he doesn’t, next day he sure will. He likes coding and is amazed by what computers can do and how they work. The technical side of AI, how it works, its applications and development process will be tackled by him (because I don’t have enough brains to do so).
In this first post, I think that we should first be defining what AI is in first place before getting into its specific usage in artistic areas. I will start with a more general explanation and examples of AI the history behind how it came to be what it is today. Then Kuyta be picking of where I left to explain how they work and the theory behind it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sir Potata</name></author><category term="intro" /><summary type="html">Who Are We?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What The _Fuck_ Is AI?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ai/2023/03/01/what-is-ai.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What The _Fuck_ Is AI?" /><published>2023-03-01T21:47:55+03:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T21:47:55+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ai/2023/03/01/what-is-ai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ai/2023/03/01/what-is-ai.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kuyta:&lt;/strong&gt; Hello to everyone again! In this post, we will discuss the magical thingamajig of AI. We will answer the questions: What is AI? How is it made? What are the forms of it? How does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will start with what the fuck is actually AI. The definition of AI varies with who you ask it to; however, 
one of the most commonly used definitions of it comes from one of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www-formal.stanford.edu/jmc/whatisai.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;John McCarthy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;’s papers: 
“It is the science and engineering of making intelligent machines, especially intelligent computer programs. 
It is related to the similar task of using computers to understand human intelligence, but AI does not have to confine itself to methods that are biologically observable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, decades before McCarthy’s paper, one of the GOATs of computing, Alan Turing, made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://redirect.cs.umbc.edu/courses/471/papers/turing.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;statement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about AI: in one of his seminars, 
he asked the question “Can machines think?” From there, he came up with a test, now famously called “The Turing Test” (how original? (Really, your surname?) 
This test is made to distinguish between human and computer-generated art, text, or anything really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors of one of the most used textbooks on AI, Stuart Russell and Peter Norvig’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://aima.cs.berkeley.edu/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 
differentiated AI into computer systems on the basis of rationality and humans, and thinking vs. acting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer Systems Based On A Human Approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systems that think like humans,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;systems that act like humans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer Systems Based on an Ideal Approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systems that think rationally,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;systems that act rationally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most AIs that are commonly used in the world—ChatGPT, Dall E 2, GPT3, and MidJourney—are based on &lt;em&gt;systems that act like humans&lt;/em&gt;. 
Like, for instance, ChatGPT tries to be a human by trying to talk like a human. It tries to have a human conversation with you. 
By contrast, &lt;em&gt;systems that think like humans&lt;/em&gt; are basically trying to learn how humans would think based on a hypothetical situation. 
For example, a problem solver might not actually solve a problem correctly; however, it will have similar thought processes to real humans who tried to solve the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a final word, we can say that AI are computational intelligences that do not have a mind of their own but are things that can mimic human thoughts and actions 
(I mean, they can mimic reeeally well these days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, I am going to give the microphone to Sir Potata to talk about AI’s decades-old history.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kuyta</name></author><category term="AI" /><summary type="html">Actually tho what is it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">All Of Our Posts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/01/every-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All Of Our Posts" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/03/01/every-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/03/01/every-post.html"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>